Duncan White Nottingham 07776 135997 duncanwhite.co.uk github.com/duncan-s-white duncanstanleywhite@gmail.com

I am a developer from Nottingham with experience of front end and back end technologies. I have just completed a 13 week full-stack software development bootcamp, which I chose to do due to its content, practical nature and the opportunity to collaborate with others. Through taking this course I have been successful in my goal to expand my knowledge of Javascript, test driven development and front end tools such as React.

Leading up to the course I was using online learning resources and working on small projects in order to advance my professional development. Since finishing the course I am continuing my independent learning by working through online tutorials for C# and Laravel. This recent exposure to the technology industry has built on my existing experience which started with my studies and continued during my time working in and running an E-commerce retail business with my brothers.

Technical Skills

Languages: Javascript, PHP, SQL

Front End: React, Material UI, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap

Back End: PSQL, MySQL, Express, NodeJS

Testing: Jest, Supertest

Experience

Northcoders - full stack software developer bootcamp

This course has enabled me to update and expand my understanding of industry standards and tools, such as Jest for test driven development and git / GitHub for collaboration and version control.

I enjoyed the regular paired projects with numerous course participants, in which I was able to demonstrate adaptive team working in response to a variety of challenges.

Personal Portfolio: https://duncanwhite.co.uk

Front End Project: React and MaterialUI front end to the API

Hosted: https://dw-nc-news.netlify.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/duncan-s-white/fe-nc-news

Back End Project: A RESTful API server, developed with Node and Express

Hosted: https://dw-nc-news.herokuapp.com/api

GitHub: https://github.com/duncan-s-white/news-api

Final Project: Pingo, a photo bingo game. React Native and Firebase mobile app.

GitHub: https://github.com/baddis01/Pingo-Final-Project

Trustee for Access Adventures (2019-Present)

In 2019 I was co-opted as a trustee for the British Disabled Waterski & Wakeboard Association during their merger with Access Adventures.

Since then I have worked with the CEO of the charity to research and setup a Constituent Relationship Management system (CiviCRM) which I administer. This automates several repetitive processes and manages the storage and maintenance of the charity's data.

Director for Electro Supplies Ltd (2010-2019)

This was a business that I owned and ran with my two brothers.

It was an E-commerce business which took in excess of £12 million worth of orders through the website during my time with the company.

My main roles were to maintain and develop the e-commerce website and administration. Some notable achievements and responsibilities were:

- Launch of e-commerce software, a customised version of OSCommerce. This
 involved extensive alterations to the administration using PHP, JQuery and CSS
 Bootstrap to fulfil the operational and business needs of the company including:
 - Installing and modifying OSCommerce add-ons, to increase functionality.
 - Developing a custom quoting system by extending and modifying the existing code and database from the orders part of the system.
 - Adding Ajax features to give a smoother user experience.
 - Theming with CSS bootstrap to improve usability and responsiveness.
- Writing PHP code to reduce repetitive staff jobs, such as processing spreadsheets.
- Participating in regular meetings, to discuss the aims and direction of the company.

Education

Southampton Solent University (2006-2008)

Completed 6 Modules for BA - Internet Applications Development

City & Islington College (2004-2005)

Access to Digital Media

Harlow Itec (2002)

European Computer Driving Licence

City & Guilds IT Diploma in Computer Applications (A Level 2 Vocational Qualification)

St. Mary's Catholic School, Bishop's Stortford, AS Levels (2000-2001)

Mathematics, Religious Studies, Biology

GCSE's (1995-2000)

10 x GCSE A* - B